A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, general correspondence, RG 2, 1940-1946 FA758
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, general correspondence, RG 2, 1940-1946
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA758
65.05 Cubic Feet Standard document boxes, 187-352, 560-562 (Stack Material)
Scope and Contents
Correspondence of The Rockefeller Foundation consists principally of material not directly connected with an institutional grant. It includes: inter-office memoranda, correspondence between field officers and the home office, extracts from officers' diaries, forms and other material relating to fellowships; casual requests for information, employment, or aid; printed matter and letters of abuse received by the Foundation. As such, the General Correspondence provides insight into the day-to-day workings of the Foundation.
Programs other than public health are not amply represented in the early portion of the General Correspondence. Material on the Division of Humanities and the Division of Social Sciences is especially scanty before 1935. After 1940, the volume of this material increases steadily. Indeed, the General Correspondence files as a whole are relatively compact up to 1940; after 1941, they expand enormously.
Some of the most important features and subjects of these files are as follows:
100: STAFF COMMUNICATIONS AND INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS
This designation applies to two distinct types of documents.
(1) STAFF COMMUNICATIONS. Much of the material under this heading consists of correspondence between or regarding staff officers (eg. a field officer and a member of the home office staff), or gives details of employment and assignment of the field officer. Thus this file is in the nature of a supplement of the Foundation's personnel records. Correspondence between retirees and active staff members is often also filed under this designation, under the names of the individuals. One will also find here inter-office correspondence from the New York headquarters. Of special interest in this connection are the memos of Raymond B. Fosdick (President of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1936-1948), which usually consist of several folders for each year indicated. Some correspondence with trustees, especially Thomas B. Debevoise, may also be found here.
(2) INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS. Correspondence between The Rockefeller Foundation and the League of Nations (especially with Arthur Sweetser) lodges under this heading and persists into the 1940s. After the establishment of the United Nations Organization in 1944/5, documentation of the Foundation's cooperation with various U.N. efforts is to be found. Of special interest are the files regarding Selskar M. Gunn and Warren Weaver's service with UNRRA (1944-1946) and John Marshall's presence as an observer at the earliest organizational meetings of UNESCO (1946-1947).
200: THE UNITED STATES (201-258: Individual States and Territories)
The largest concentration of material is to be found under this designation. It is also the most miscellaneous in character. Correspondence ranges from communications with Federal agencies and departments, to letters of advice, records of interviews, appeals for aid, employment inquiries, and crank mail.
The vast bulk of these files dating between 1927 and 1939 relates to the work of the International Health Division, supplementing material previously processed as RG 5. This includes material on grants to state boards of health, training grants for public health personnel at stations in Ohio or Mississippi, and advice on administrative matters. Following the practice of the IHD, most of these earlier files were arranged under an individual state heading rather than under that of the nation as a whole. By 1935 most of the IHD activities had declined as funding became available to the states through the Federal government for this purpose. Correspondence with the individual state agencies shrank accordingly. The advisory functions of the IHD thereafter took place mainly in the form of pooling information (and occasionally personnel) with the U.S. Public Health Service.
Those states files which remain sizeable after 1935 (such as 216: Illinois-University of Chicago, and 248: Tennessee: TVA) do not relate primarily to IHD activities. In 1951, the use of state numbers in filing was almost totally abandoned.
200: UNITED STATES PUBLIC HEALTH SERVICE
During World War II, the Foundation maintained close ties with USPHS, as reflected in the large file of correspondence between Foundation officers and various USPHS officials. This file refers particularly to the Foundation's effort to provide yellow fever vaccine to the Armed Forces. Also of interest for this period is a set of weekly reports on the incidence of virulent disease (plague, smallpox, etc.) around the world.
200E: FELLOWSHIPS
The earlier portion of material so designated (through 1935) is taken up with grants for training public health personnel as requested by various state boards of health. It thus amplifies the documentation of IHD activities noted above. This material includes both declinations as well as acceptances.
Similar material through the 1930s is to be found under 200S: Social Science Research Council, consisting mostly of application forms and correspondence concerning potential SSRC grantees.
For the years 1945-46, an extensive file of Postwar Fellowships follows the regular fellowship file in the General Correspondence. While the character of Foundation support of these Fellows is unclear, the advisory function of Foundation officers in their selection and placement is amply documented here.
300-833: INDIVIDUAL NATIONAL FILES
The files under this heading include administrative and budgetary material for field offices, reports of interviews with potential grantees, governmental and educational figures, diary extracts (usually travel notes, sometimes quite extensive), and miscellaneous correspondence with private and public scientific or cultural institutions and individuals. The majority of this material (especially before 1935) continues the records of the IHD in its international program (see RG 5), and deals primarily with public health programs and medical training. After 1935, the subject matter in the files becomes more diversified.
Scattered throughout these series are observations by Foundation officers on the political and social climate around the world. The Rockefeller Foundation maintained political neutrality regarding the internal affairs of host countries, and cooperated closely with governmental ministries and state-controlled universities -- especially in the areas of public health and the social sciences. Nevertheless, a close watch was kept on developments affecting intellectual freedom and the general climate of cooperation which the Foundation saw as the main prerequisite for performing or sponsoring significant work. This is reflected in the General Correspondence files, where one may find contemporary eyewitness reports and informed outside opinions on such phenomena of this century as the development of Fascism in Europe, the growth of Communism in eastern Europe and China, and the rise or fall of various dictatorships in Latin America.
Large quantities of material may be found under the following headings:
300: South America 315: Cuba 400: Great Britain 427: Canada 437: Jamaica 464: India (including 464.1: Mysore and 464.5: Travancore, through 1944) 500: France 601: China 700: Europe
The bulk of these files indicates either high levels of Foundation activity or the presence of a field office in the country concerned, and thus an "Administration" file will be found here as well as material filed alphabetically or under a program letter. Special features include the 1945-46, 500E file (France-Government Fellowships), which consist of material similar to that described under 200E for the same period. Under 700, one will also find material on the Paris Field Office supplementing that processed separately as RG 6.1.
SPECIAL TOPIC: REFUGEE SCHOLARS, 1933-1946
The General Correspondence contains a mass of material on the plight of European scholars deprived of means or work by the rise of Fascism. This material is similar and supplementary to that found in RG 1 under the same heading. Most of the material in the General Correspondence bearing on this topic may be found as listed below:
717: Germany--Refugee Scholars, 1933-1939 789: Poland-----Refugee Scholars, 1936-1939 200: U.S.---------Refugee Scholars, 1940-1945
These files generally fall into two parts:
(1) A chronological file entitled "Exiled Scholars" which consists of officer's correspondence, diary extracts, lists of exiled academics compiled from various sources, correspondence with various committees and institutions engaged in placing these scholars, and copies of the minutes of those committees with which The Rockefeller Foundation cooperated most closely.
(2) An alphabetical file of correspondence with or concerning individual scholars whose placement the Foundation sponsored or financed in part.
(3) Much material filed under 700: Europe and individual European country numbers (including 400: Great Britain, and 805: Turkey) during the period 1933-1945 also deals with this topic.
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
- General Correspondence, 1940
  - International, 1940; 1940/100
    - (A-D), 1940 (Box 187, Folder 1337)
    - (E-F), 1940 (Box 187, Folder 1338)
    - Fosdick, Raymond B. (1), 1940 (Box 187, Folder 1339)
    - Fosdick, Raymond B. (2), 1940 (Box 187, Folder 1340)
    - F-H, 1940 (Box 187, Folder 1341)
    - I-K, 1940 (Box 187, Folder 1342)
    - K-N, 1940 (Box 187, Folder 1343)
    - O-S, 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1344)
    - S-W, 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1345)
    - W-Z, 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1346)
    - International - Medical Sciences, 1940; 1940/100.A
      Medical sciences
      - Staff Communications and International Affairs, 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1346)
    - International - Hookworm, 1940; 1940/100.H
      Hookworm disease
      - Staff Communications and International Affairs, 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1346)
    - International - Malaria, 1940; 1940/100.I
      Malaria
      - Staff Communications and International Affairs, 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1346)
    - International - Yellow Fever, 1940; 1940/100.O
      Yellow fever
      - Staff Communications and International Affairs, 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1346)
    - International - Tuberculosis, 1940; 1940/100.T
      Tuberculosis
      - Staff Communications and International Affairs, 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1346)
  - United States, 1940; 1940/200
    United States
    - United States - (A-American E), 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1347)
    - United States - (American F-R), 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1348)
    - United States - (American R-S), 1940 (Box 188, Folder 1349)
    - United States - (American Scientific Congress), 1940 (Box 189, Folder 1350)
    - United States - (American S-Z - As), 1940 (Box 189, Folder 1351)
    - United States - (As-Bz), 1940 (Box 189, Folder 1352)
    - United States - (C-Ce), 1940 (Box 189, Folder 1353)
    - United States - (Co-Cz), 1940 (Box 189, Folder 1354)
    - United States - (D-Fe), 1940 (Box 190, Folder 1355)
    - United States - (Fe-Ge), 1940 (Box 190, Folder 1356)
    - United States - (Gl-Hof), 1940 (Box 190, Folder 1357)
    - United States - (Hog-In), 1940 (Box 190, Folder 1358)
    - United States - (In-Kz), 1940 (Box 190, Folder 1359)
    - United States - (L-Ma), 1940 (Box 190, Folder 1360)
    - United States - (Me-Mo), 1940 (Box 191, Folder 1361)
    - United States - (Mu-Na), 1940 (Box 191, Folder 1362)
    - United States - (Ne-Pe), 1940 (Box 191, Folder 1363)
    - United States - (Ph-Re), 1940 (Box 191, Folder 1364)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (A-B), 1940 (Box 191, Folder 1365)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (D-E), 1940 (Box 191, Folder 1366)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (F-G), 1940 (Box 192, Folder 1367)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (H), 1940 (Box 192, Folder 1368)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (J-K), 1940 (Box 192, Folder 1369)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (L-M), 1940 (Box 192, Folder 1370)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (N-R), 1940 (Box 192, Folder 1371)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (Si-T), 1940 (Box 193, Folder 1372)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (S-Se), 1940 (Box 193, Folder 1373)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (U-V), 1940 (Box 193, Folder 1374)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (W), 1940 (Box 193, Folder 1375)
    - United States - Refugee Scholars - (X-Z), 1940 (Box 193, Folder 1376)
    - United States - (Ri-Rz), 1940 (Box 193, Folder 1377)
    - United States - (S), 1940 (Box 194, Folder 1378)
    - United States - (T-Un), 1940 (Box 194, Folder 1379)
    - United States - U.S. (A-Z), 1940 (Box 194, Folder 1380)
    - United States - (U-Wo), 1940 (Box 194, Folder 1381)
    - United States - (Wo-Z), 1940 (Box 194, Folder 1382)
    - United States - Medical Sciences, 1940; 1940/200.A
      - United States, 1940 (Box 194, Folder 1383)
    - United States - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/200.E
      Fellowships
      - United States, 1940 (Box 194, Folder 1383)
      - United States - (E-Z), 1940 (Box 195, Folder 1384)
    - United States - Malaria, 1940; 1940/200.I
      - United States, 1940 (Box 195, Folder 1385)
    - United States - Public Health Education, 1940; 1940/200.L
      Schools of public health
      - United States, 1940 (Box 195, Folder 1385)
    - United States - Humanities and Arts, 1940; 1940/200.R
      Humanities
      - United States, 1940 (Box 195, Folder 1386)
    - United States - Social Sciences, 1940; 1940/200.S
      Social sciences
      - United States - Social Science Research Council, 1940 (Box 195, Folder 1387)
      - United States - Social Science Research Council, 1940 (Box 195, Folder 1388)
  - Alabama, 1940; 1940/201
    Alabama
    - Alabama, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1389)
  - Arkansas, 1940; 1940/204
    Arkansas
    - Arkansas, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1389)
  - California, 1940; 1940/205
    California
    - California, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1389)
    - California - University of California, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1390)
    - California - Medical Sciences, 1940; 1940/205.A
      - California, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
    - California - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/205.E
      - California, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
    - California - Humanities and Arts, 1940; 1940/205.R
      - California, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
    - California - Social Sciences, 1940; 1940/205.S
      - California, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
  - Colorado, 1940; 1940/207
    Colorado
    - Colorado, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
    - Colorado - Social Sciences, 1940; 1940/207.S
      - Colorado, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
  - Connecticut, 1940; 1940/208
    Connecticut
    - Connecticut, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
  - Florida, 1940; 1940/211
    Florida
    - Florida, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
  - Georgia, 1940; 1940/212
    Georgia
    - Georgia, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1391)
  - Illinois, 1940; 1940/216
    Illinois
    - Illinois, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1392)
  - Iowa, 1940; 1940/218
    Iowa
    - Iowa, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1393)
  - Kansas, 1940; 1940/219
    Kansas
    - Kansas, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1393)
  - Kentucky, 1940; 1940/220
    Kentucky
    - Kentucky, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1393)
  - Louisiana, 1940; 1940/221
    Louisiana
    - Louisiana, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1393)
    - Louisiana - Social Sciences, 1940; 1940/221.S
      - Louisiana, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1393)
  - Maryland, 1940; 1940/223
    Maryland
    - Maryland, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1393)
  - Massachusetts, 1940; 1940/224
    Massachusetts
    - Massachusetts, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1393)
  - Minnesota, 1940; 1940/226
    Minnesota
    - Minnesota, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1394)
  - Mississippi, 1940; 1940/227
    Mississippi
    - Mississippi, 1940 (Box 196, Folder 1394)
  - Missouri, 1940; 1940/228
    Missouri
    - Missouri, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1395)
  - Montana, 1940; 1940/229
    Montana
    - Montana, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1395)
  - New Jersey, 1940; 1940/233
    New Jersey
    - New Jersey, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1395)
  - North Carolina, 1940; 1940/236
    North Carolina
    - North Carolina, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1395)
    - North Carolina, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1396)
    - North Carolina - Medical Sciences, 1940; 1940/236.A
      - North Carolina, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1396)
    - North Carolina - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 1940; 1940/236.D
      Agriculture; Science
      - North Carolina, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1396)
  - North Dakota, 1940; 1940/237
    North Dakota
    - North Dakota, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1396)
  - Ohio, 1940; 1940/238
    Ohio
    - Ohio, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1396)
  - Oregon, 1940; 1940/240
    Oregon
    - Oregon, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1396)
  - Pennsylvania, 1940; 1940/241
    Pennsylvania
    - Pennsylvania, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1396)
    - Pennsylvania, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1397)
    - Pennsylvania - Medical Sciences, 1940; 1940/241.A
      - Pennsylvania, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1397)
    - Pennsylvania - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 1940; 1940/241.D
      - Pennsylvania, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1397)
    - Pennsylvania - Humanities and Arts, 1940; 1940/241.R
      - Pennsylvania, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1397)
  - Philippines, 1940; 1940/242
    Philippines
    - Philippine Islands, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1397)
    - Philippine Islands, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1397)
    - Philippines - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/242.E
      - Philippine Islands, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1397)
  - Rhode Island, 1940; 1940/244
    Rhode Island
    - Rhode Island, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1398)
  - South Carolina, 1940; 1940/246
    South Carolina
    - South Carolina, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1398)
  - South Dakota, 1940; 1940/247
    South Dakota
    - South Dakota, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1398)
  - Tennessee, 1940; 1940/248
    Tennessee
    - Tennessee - State Board of Health, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1399)
    - Tennessee, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1400)
  - Texas, 1940; 1940/249
    Texas
    - Texas, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1401)
  - Utah, 1940; 1940/250
    Utah
    - Utah, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1401)
  - Virginia, 1940; 1940/252
    Virginia
    - Virginia, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1401)
    - Virginia - Humanities and Arts, 1940; 1940/252.R
      - Virginia, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1401)
  - Washington, 1940; 1940/253
    Washington (State)
    - Washington, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1401)
  - West Virginia, 1940; 1940/254
    West Virginia
    - West Virginia, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1401)
  - Wisconsin, 1940; 1940/255
    Wisconsin
    - Wisconsin, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1401)
  - Virgin Islands, 1940; 1940/257
    United States Virgin Islands
    - Virgin Islands - Tuberculosis, 1940; 1940/257.T
      - Virgin Islands, 1940 (Box 197, Folder 1401)
  - Latin America, 1940; 1940/300
    Latin America
    - Latin America - General, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1402)
    - Latin America, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1403)
    - LAM-1 Lamber, Robert A. "Latin American Diary", 1940 (Box 560, Folder 3806)
      General note
      Stack Material
    - Latin America - Medical Sciences, 1940; 1940/300.A
      - Latin America, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1404)
    - Latin America - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 1940; 1940/300.D
      - Latin America, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1404)
    - Latin America - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/300.E
      - Latin America, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1404)
    - Latin America - Humanities and Arts, 1940; 1940/300.R
      - Latin America, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1404)
      - Latin America, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1405)
      - LEO Leonard, I. A. "Record of Ideas and Persons Met, 1937-1940" (Box 560, Folder 3807)
    - Latin America - Social Sciences, 1940; 1940/300.S
      - Latin America, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1405)
  - Argentina, 1940; 1940/301
    Argentina
    - Argentina, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1406)
    - Argentina - Nursing, 1940; 1940/301.C
      Nursing
      - Argentina, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1406)
    - Argentina - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/301.E
      - Argentina, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 1406)
  - Bolivia, 1940; 1940/303
    Bolivia
    - Bolivia, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1407)
  - Brazil, 1940; 1940/305
    Brazil
    - Brazil, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1407)
    - Brazil - Yellow Fever, 1940; 1940/305.O
      - LAB-2 Laboratory for the Study of Yellow Fever "The Organization and detailed Procedures of the Vaccine Division of the Yellow Fever Laboratory", 1940 (Box 560, Folder 3808)
  - Chile, 1940; 1940/309
    Chile
    - Chile, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1407)
    - Chile - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/309.E
      - Chile, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1407)
  - Colombia, 1940; 1940/311
    Colombia
    - Colombia, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1407)
  - Costa Rica, 1940; 1940/313
    Costa Rica
    - Costa Rica, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1407)
  - Cuba, 1940; 1940/315
    Cuba
    - Cuba, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1408)
  - Ecuador, 1940; 1940/317
    Ecuador
    - Ecuador, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1409)
    - Ecuador - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/317.E
      - Ecuador, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1409)
    - Ecuador - Malaria, 1940; 1940/317.I
      - Ecuador, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1409)
  - Guatemala, 1940; 1940/319
    Guatemala
    - Guatemala, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1409)
  - Mexico, 1940; 1940/323
    Mexico
    - Mexico - (A-I), 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1409)
    - Mexico - (J-Z), 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1410)
    - Mexico - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/323.E
      - Mexico, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1410)
    - Mexico - Humanities and Arts, 1940; 1940/323.R
      - LEO Leonard, Irving A. "Notes and Comments on a Visit to Mexico", 1940 (Box 560, Folder 3809)
  - Nicaragua, 1940; 1940/325
    Nicaragua
    - Nicaragua, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1410)
  - Panama, 1940; 1940/327
    Panama
    - Panama, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1411)
    - Panama - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/327.E
      - Panama, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1411)
    - Panama - Tuberculosis, 1940; 1940/327.T
      - Panama, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1411)
  - Peru, 1940; 1940/331
    Peru
    - Peru, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1411)
    - Peru - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/331.E
      - Peru, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1411)
  - El Salvador, 1940; 1940/333
    El Salvador
    - El Salvador, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1411)
  - Dominican Republic, 1940; 1940/335
    Dominican Republic
    - El Salvador, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1411)
  - Uruguay, 1940; 1940/337
    Uruguay
    - Uruguay, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1411)
  - Venezuela, 1940; 1940/339
    Venezuela
    - Venezuela - Health, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1412)
    - Venezuela - Health, 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1413)
    - Venezuela - (A-Z), 1940 (Box 199, Folder 1414)
    - Venezuela - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/339.E
      - Venezuela, 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1414)
  - Great Britain, 1940; 1940/400
    Great Britain
    - Great Britain, 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1415)
  - England, 1940; 1940/401
    England
    - England - (A-M), 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1415)
    - England - (N-R), 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1416)
    - England - (S-Z), 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1417)
    - England - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 1940; 1940/401.D
      - England, 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1418)
    - England - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 1940; 1940/401.E
      - England, 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1418)
    - England - Social Sciences, 1940; 1940/401.S
      - England, 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1418)
  - Ireland, 1940; 1940/403
    Ireland
    - Ireland, 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1418)